At
7PM
on Monday, 12/26/2021.
I note
by the
participants
in the call that,
Commissioner Judd Florissant
and Commissioner William Monroe
are present, as well as myself, Chairman Elliott.
And I note also that
alternate member Ed Smith is not present.
Item three of the agenda. Do we have any changes or additions,
changes in order or additions to the agenda?
None that I'm aware of.
Okay, and seeing none, I'll proceed then to approval of the minutes
for the meeting of 11/01/2021.
And to get things going, I'll make a motion that we
approve
those minutes.
A second would be appreciated.
I'll second. Okay,
>> so moved and seconded to approve minutes.
Are there any
necessary revisions?
I did not note any in my perusal.
Give the members a moment to refresh.
Nay.
>> Okay,
if there are no
revisions suggested,
I'll proceed to ask for a vote on the motion
by roll call.
Judd Larson?
Aye.
William Monroe?
>> And I vote aye as well.
Okay,
we have now an opportunity for public comment. If any members of the public, anyone on the call, wants to comment about any of the
agenda items or any previous
actions of the Commission,
this is the time.
Oh, wait a minute. I just noticed that Ed Smith is on the call, so you can revise
that for me. Thank you, Abby.
Okay,
seeing no hands raised, I'll proceed to
item six,
new business. We have
three new applications
or well, we have two new applications
and a jurisdictional
review.
First of all,
Inland Wetlands Watercourse Commission 2126
from Todd Perkins at 1 Lakeside Drive,
who wishes to rebuild
and
remortor
an existing
stone wall on the Andover Lake Shoreline.
Let's see now. Is the
applicant or representative present on the call? I'm
>> right here. Can you I hear see you there. Okay, yeah. Okay, great.
Good evening. I'm Todd.
>> Right. First of all, let me just run by the commissioners. Do you have any
immediate questions
based on looking at? And then I'll ask Mr. Perkins to walk us through.
>> I didn't see where we had the Alma approval
letter in the file there.
I know it was as well.
Mr. Perkins?
>> That was applied for
the same day
that I went down to the town hall and
submitted
for the permit.
I'm
not sure what the holdup is. I'll have to look into it.
>> We'll hope that it's ready by our next meeting.
And
yeah, it wouldn't be a bad idea to
check it out. So,
Perkins, did you want to speak to that application
there, which we have open now?
>> Well, I mean, I bought my house here
on Lakeside
Drive back in 2016,
and the wall wasn't in noticeably poor condition,
or I would have asked to have it fixed before I settled
with the mortgage company.
But it has sense,
and I'm not sure if it's ice or not. I don't know what's
destroyed it so much, but it's
It's toppling now into the lake.
And as it does so, I can see that it was mortared before. It's a very old stone wall.
And
I
found a
private
person who does this kind of thing,
and I would like to get it repaired.
It's as simple as that. I'm not changing anything. I'm having him
restock the stones that fell down
and
re replace
the the mortar.
>> And the mortar portions of the wall.
Right. We have, we have, of course, photographs
that
Agent Wagner provided,
documenting And
the condition of the
I think your
point is very easily taken
well,
you'll recall, William,
Robert Frost, something there is that does not like a wall.
>> So, whatever That's my neighbor's property. Oh, there we go. That's
>> my neighbor's. That's that's the application 27,
Abby. I think we want this is number 26.
>> Yes, that's my mess right there.
Doesn't look much like a wall anymore.
>> I noticed some activity
in
the fifth photograph
on the
area alongside the dock and where it's going to be remorted.
Yeah, he's ready to go.
>> Okay. Was
there a fill in there or what's
that activity from all that So fresh
>> what's
happened is because
the
integrity of the wall has been breached so much,
Cheney Brook is
pulling
dirt out of my property
little by little over time
and creating
a hazard
behind the wall
land side.
So I put some dirt in there to try to fill those.
I mean, some of them you stepped in them, they were at least a foot deep.
So
that's why that's there, but it's clean fill.
It's all clean.
And then the Mason guy, stuff is in the background there, is itching to get started. I keep telling him that I have to wait until I have approval from y'all.
>> Indeed,
and
Technically,
probably that fill activity should be included in the permit also.
Don't know. Agent Wagner, do you have any, thoughts on that?
>> Was that to me? Yeah.
I'm sorry, I didn't hear you. Okay, I'm sorry, the question,
>> I'm noting the fill on
photograph number five.
I was
speculating that technically that might be,
perhaps should be included in the permit application since it is an activity,
you know, in the Upland Review area,
not
to mention right on the lake shore.
You know, impending the Alma approval, I
don't see any issue with it, but just, again, as a matter of form,
the
entire activity
should
be subject to permit.
>> Understood. So I would go down again to the town hall and write an addendum perhaps?
>> I think that would suffice, yeah. Okay. Or just submit it
by,
you know, just, I think if you submit it by email to Agent Wagner,
that would be sufficient.
>> Okay. Yeah, we could just add a comment
to the
existing application.
Okay.
Moving on, any questions from the other commissioners?
Nay.
Okay. Jed, any comment or question?
No, I'm all set. Okay,
>> well,
Ms. Perkins, you're aware that we can't act on this application tonight. We have to defer that to our next meeting.
And
so, in the meantime, we can take care of that little addendum
and also hopefully get the approval
from Alma on
record
so that we would be able to act on the application
>> at the next meeting. Okay. Okay? Those are the I two
think Joe spoke
up.
No?
What was that?
>> I I thought you said that you had something to add.
>> No. No, that was a I was just saying we could add, you know, we'll just add the fill to the existing application.
Yeah.
A little write up. It's nothing.
>> I'll do that by email. I'll also email
Alma and see what the holdup is. Think that
when I went down to the to the office, they told me they had to wait for a couple weeks. I think it was a couple of weeks at least.
>> Yeah, usually most applications,
though,
the the ALMA approval comes in, you know, halfway through the the next month. It seems like there's a little bit of a lag.
I know the other two that we have, they they came in, the week after the
the November meeting.
>> This was submitted on
eleventwenty three.
I'll email her tonight. I don't expect to hear from her tonight, but I'll get that ball
rolling.
>> Okay, great. So, we'll move on then to the next item on the agenda.
Mr. Perkins, you can be excused from the meeting if you want to click on that little red button.
Okay.
>> Next application is IWWC
2127,
Gary McCullough, right next door, who wants to restore an existing beach and
reconstruct
a dock
on the shoreline.
I
see that
Mr. DuBois is on
the call.
And
okay,
so
let's see now. I guess the
circumstances of this application is that the
work is as it were already underway
with
several loads of sand, in place and ready to spread.
So,
Mr. McCullough, Ms. Oops,
wait a minute. Who are we on here?
Oh,
Mr. McCullough is the oh, I'm sorry. Misspoke there.
So,
Mr. McCullough, if you wanted to speak to the application there.
>> Yes. Hi. Can you hear me? Yeah. Oh great. So yeah, I'm a new resident
and
so you know there was an existing
sand beach there was
you know kind of dirty and kind of just you know, hasn't been attended to.
So it was my own ignorance that I didn't know I had to do to, you know, apply like this
when I had the sand delivered because I, you know, heard the lake was lowered for
maintenance things and that's what people did.
So for that, I apologize for my ignorance there. So as soon as I found that out, then I started the application process,
provided
the information.
And there's really kind of two things. One is the
replenishing the sand and then the removal of the existing dock,
which was very deteriorated,
rotting
and
barely able to stand on.
Know, wanted to get rid of that
and at some point replace it.
But, the first phase is really just kind of clean up and
go from there. That's really my objective is
to do that and do it in a proper way.
>> Okay,
yeah, I get the point here. I take it that the
Alamo must have approved sometime in the past
creating a sand beach on what would otherwise be a mudflat at this time of year,
and
dock likewise must have also been approved at some point. But my question was how much of theokay,
the
drawing that I have herethis
is again in the supporting documentation,
Abby. I guess
the
last two pages of the application,
and hold on a second here. I'm gonna
reorient
the figure so that it's
a little more visible.
I'm working on my own desktop
here
as opposed to Abby's desktop.
>> So, are you wanting to look at the site plans?
>> Yeah,
as you said, it seemsyeah,
right, theyeah,
site plans.
So, it looks like you have
feet of
lakefront
there
that you're proposing
to restore
with the sand?
Yeah, 25 across in like.
>> And about and about 20 feet, so
about 500 square feet area
that you're going to restore
with fresh sand.
And to hand you're spread that,
weather permitting and all all
that.
Okay, yeah,
and then the then the dock
is on.
A different portion of the
>> yeah, it's yeah, it's just to the right of the Sandy Beach there.
>> Okay, yeah, yeah, that's I see that it's clear now from looking at the plan there. Okay,
they were clear on what needs to be done.
Any
question from members of the board?
>> I I got a question.
Yeah, go ahead. Oh, I see those that one lakeside.
That's your neighbor on one side and the seven lakeside is your neighbor on the other side.
I was I was thinking that that there was
look look like on this drawing,
it was like a lit the lake was on both sides of it.
But it's just dresses
that are
put on there.
I don't have a question, actually. I answered my question.
>> Good,
best way to do it.
Commissioner Larson,
questions or comments?
>> So is the sand intended to actually go down onto the lake bed?
>> It goes out probably about
five
to 10 feet, I'd say.
There's an existing sand bed out there,
So I was just going to go cover over what's already there.
>> And have you
approached Alma asking for their
permission, concurrence, whatever it is they give to go do this?
>> Have emailed them
asking if there's required permission for,
you know, refurbishing
an existing,
sand bed there,
but I didn't really get a response.
And I did follow-up and asked what should we do
in parallel with this activity?
And I was reading through some of the
rules
that I could find about that. And
all I could find was like if you were to repair
a dock or replace a dock,
you know, it would have to be in the same same spot that the original was in.
And there was a list of approved materials,
but there was nothing from Alma there that I saw that said, well, if it's an existing,
you know,
sand play, you know, sand area
that
they would require
an email or something of approval. I mean, I I can reach out to them again, but are are they invited to these meetings or?
>> The
okay. The Admiral Lake Management Association
is technically the owner of the lake bed.
Yeah. Therefore, their permission is required
for any activity
that intrudes onto the lakebed, and that would certainly include
depositing sand
on the lakebed,
you know, any place below high water mark.
And so that's why all repairs to walls and so forth
on
the Andor Of The Lakeshore
concurrently require
approval by Alma.
Now, think that your situation, sand
beaches are not very common on Andover Lake,
with the exception of the Alpoa Beach
Lake Road, that you know, they
may not have a specific policy in writing,
but you know from this
Commission and from the regulations that we're working under,
as they say, since they are the property owner of record,
we have to have
a statement
from Alma to the effect that they have approved
your proposed activity.
Okay. So, just make sure that they understand what you're doing. Again, as
agent Weyer pointed out, typically there's a
lag
between the time that
permission is granted
and the time that we hear from them, or you as the
applicant hear from them,
but we would hope that it would be
in advance of our next meeting in January.
Right. Okay.
>> So again,
as we, as we said previously,
we can't deal with your application tonight under state statute, we're required to wait at least two weeks, and practically speaking, that means we won't deal with it until our next regular meeting.
>> Okay.
So what I need to do then is,
well, I guess I'll call. I do have the number of
a couple of the members there. So I'll
call and
get that moving.
>> I don't recall off the top of my head who usually issues those permissions.
It's
on a couple of letters that I have
buried in a folder
on my desktop.
Joe, do you remember off the top of your head?
Some of them say, he is.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
Just just as an aside or just for clarity,
I I did speak with somebody,
and I was left with impression
that they needed like input from you guys
saying it's okay from your perspective.
It's kind of like the chicken or the egg here, right? So
you guys, we can't move until
or
you know, you can't approve it till they say it's okay. And then I kind of got the idea that
the next step was to get your okay. And then they say if it's okay with you, it's okay with them. That kind thing. I think they were, I think you may have been, there may have been a little misunderstanding
>> there because,
you know, we
are quite clear on that, and we have applications
in hand,
where we have
the permission
statements,
and we're,
you know, now going to act on them,
having received that
permission
from Alpo from Alma. Excuse me. Alma, yeah. Yeah, it's definitely we've got to have Alma before we can rule
on the application.
Okay,
well, it's clear now.
>> So,
Chairman Elliott, would it be inappropriate to discuss concerns with the application with respect to
inland wetlands commission tonight or do we wait until we're quite open to comment
>> at this point. And if you have
comments on the application,
go right ahead.
>> Well, I do have an application because
most of the, you know, people living on the lake are
concerned with the extent that sediment is filling up the lake
ever so slowly, but it only heads one direction. The lake gets fuller
and fuller of sediment.
And
in the action proposed here that
actually increases
that rate of sediment or sand
going into the lake. So I think that is
quite detrimental to the health of the lake.
>> I would tend to agree with that comment and
note that it seemed to me likely that some of the sand
that is currently
extending out onto the lake bed below the
high water mark
probably came from whatever sand was deposited there
by previous owners of the property.
>> Yeah, I'm not sure, you know, how
well I know that
inland wetlands
watercourse regulations
have had
increased emphasis over recent years.
I think there's several pieces of property around the lake that have
sand there and it's not replenished
probably because of the detriment to the lake.
>> The
right now, well, yeah,
that side of the lake is
kind of, it's not very deep at all, right? I mean, it's
Right now it's
all kind of dirt all the way out. So it's very shallow.
I don't know that it would,
you know, travel very far. It's only about five feet out now. So it looks like that was there. But I mean, I'm I'm no expert. I'm just stating, you know, what what I see.
But, yeah, I guess
we need to
get with Alma.
>> You know. Mean, this analogous is all case that I can think of is the
lake wall proposal
on the other side. I can't remember the
address off the top of my head, but
the original proposal called for creating a seawall that went straight along
the way and
basically cut through
a tiny little cove,
but they had proposed to actually fill in that area. And our wetlands agent
at the time, Mr. Valente,
was quite adamant about
not wanting to approve that little bit because it would involve bringing fill
into the lakeshore.
And so, although obviously we don't want to be ruling prematurely on this, I certainly think we want to have a statement from
Alma
and a considered opinion on whether they still consider this to be an appropriate activity.
Okay. You know, the
original sand may have been deposited
under
guidelines
that are well or under considerations
that have been subsequently
modified.
Are these guidelines published someplace? Well,
>> I I would have to say informal.
And no, as far as I'm aware, there there are no
published guidelines from Alma.
Jed, are you aware of any?
>> I just know that if you go to the website, it says that any activity that takes place
on the lake, whether it's a dock
in,
you know, that's the one that we most commonly see or the stone wall
that requires Alma's
permission because they are the property owner. So it would make sense that
in this case we would need Alma's permission too.
Although I think it's clearly stated in our wetlands regulations
that we don't fill in the wetlands.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, I mean,
I don't know all the regulations.
It's just like,
from my perspective,
was, you know, sand. I'm just kind of putting,
you know, some sand on the on the ground to have a little beach,
>> but But we we understand the intent,
and again,
I we
we would certainly,
the bare minimum, we would need
permission from ALMA
for that. Okay. And, you know, and further,
I think that we need to
have a discussion
about
the, you know, the second point would be then the overall propriety
of
essentially putting
fill in a well. Yeah, it's not much. It's a few yards, but fill is fill and wetlands are wetlands,
and
we have state mandated regulations
regarding
wetlands activities.
So, I think we need to take a close look at whether
this
action
is
permissible
under
the,
again, the statutory regulations
that we are
obligated
to enforce.
>> Yeah,
yeah.
Okay. So, I mean, I'm just
through this whole thing. I've been kind of looking for guidance, so I'm getting that now.
And
so
the guidance is to get with Alma,
get their feedback into this, and then submit that
feedback back to you
and then have
another meeting.
>> Right, yeah. And again, I urge you to communicate,
whatever you have you get from Alma. Communicate that to Agent Wagner.
And,
you know, as I said, that way we'll make sure we get it into the record for this application,
and we'll have it
to
consider it. You know, we'll have it for our review
and action on the application
at our next meeting. Okay.
All right. Well, thank you for the guidance. All right. Any other questions or comments on the application?
If none, then we'll move along
to
whatever is next on the agenda.
Okay, yeah, the jurisdictional
ruling.
Mr. McCullough, thanks for
jumping into the call. And
as I told previous, you can certainly excuse yourself from the meeting now.
I'll make sure you're dying to see how everything works here.
Okay, thank you. You're welcome. Okay, so next we have
a jurisdictional
review.
Hold on a second while I open this.
So, we're being asked essentially to determine
if
a
wetlands activity application
is required
for proposed
timber harvest
on a property at 37 Boston Hill Road,
the owner Kathleen Sedaris.
And
let's see now, Donald Dubois
or Dubois or
Good evening. Is the
forester, I guess, in proposing
to do the work.
Who'd like to speak to the application?
>> I would. Can everybody hear me? Can
everyone hear me?
Yes.
Great.
>> I'm
Don Dubois,
founder of Dubois Forestry and Land Management Professionals from Brooklyn, Connecticut.
I'm here tonight on behalf of Kathleen Sedaris,
who owns land at 37
Boston Hill Road in Andover, Connecticut.
Before you, you should have a notification of timber harvest
regarding the removal of some dead and dying ash trees from the property due to the emerald ash borer,
dead and dying oak trees that resulted from recent gypsy moth defoliation
and some red maple with defect.
The property has a
perennial
brook called Straddle Brook which bisects the property from west to east.
In front of you there should be a forest type map, a vegetation type map, and a topographical
map
which shows it clearly.
We proposed to install a temporary stream crossing
across the perennial brook straddle brook as to prevent any impact to the stream channel.
These are if you're not familiar with portable bridges, wooden mats that you've probably seen moving about in town on trucks here and there. And they're meant to be placed over the stream above the water flow, not to restrict the water flow, but to
prevent the movement of sediment and erosion into the stream channel during the tree removal operation.
The completion of the operation,
temporary stream crossings are removed. Most forest products harvesters today own their own bridges. Bridges.
There's a secondary
crossing prior to the Straddle Brook Crossing, which is an intermittent brook.
If you go out there right now, you would probably find that this brook is not flowing.
Even though we've had all this water this summer.
This crossing requires just the placement of a little bit of corduroy into the channel
and then its removal
at the completion of the tree removal operation.
So our goal here is to remove
dead and dying trees in order to concentrate the growth potential of the site onto the better quality trees. There are some really good quality trees here, including sugar maple, hickory,
birch, and some of the oak trees that have actually responded from recent defoliations, and they're doing quite well.
This is typically referred to as a salvage or a release thinning.
We're removing dead and dying trees, we're salvaging those trees, and we're releasing for future growth the advanced regeneration in the understory.
This property was thinned about thirty years ago,
and in the initial thinning,
there was a lot of natural regeneration that came about. And so we're trying to shed some sunlight onto this advanced regeneration
and to promote its growth.
The log loading area is located in the property's Southwest corner just off of Boston Hill Road.
There is an existing
log loading area that was utilized
thirty years ago
It's
not no. Thank you. Yes
Do
you have a topo map handy? Can we go to the next is the topo map available
There you go.
There you go. Wonderful. If you look in the
lower left hand corner of the property, just next to the word hill, you'll see a red dot And that is the proposed log loading area. This is an area that was used previously.
If you drive by there now, you will see remnants of logs
and woody chunks that were left there thirty years ago.
But if you look just to the east of this landing area, there's an existing access road
that comes on to the property and actually goes straight back to the,
what do you call it? There's a structure there.
It's
a metal building,
a military building. What was it called?
You see, I forget the name of the structure, but there's this existing driveway
that goes,
to the structure
and
is simply a better location
for the road.
It's it's further away from the wetlands. It's more stable.
It has a better log loading area is level and well drained.
So
you know based on our site inspection we decided it would just be a better location
for the log loading area in order to mitigate any impact
to wetlands
and to prevent any movement
of, soils onto the public highway.
So if you look at the site, it's it's I can't I I'm drawing a blank. I'm sorry. I'm just drawing a blank on the name of the structure. It's a it's a metal frame but that's it hot that you're talking about there thank you
yes
their existing driveway that used to go that goes to the quasi hot if you drive in there it's it's just a perfect location and as you drive into the left it's well drained it's open Just it just makes sense to locate it there rather than on the existing log loading area, which is just it
is a high risk of impact if you use the existing area. So we're proposing to move the log loading area just slightly to the east of of that red dot that you see in the map and the landowners are in agreement with this
it's pretty straightforward the
forest products harvester is hull forest products they won the job
they're going to be required to harden the log loading area they're going to be bringing in a riprap stone
This is to, you know, prevent any movement
of soil onto the highway.
Typically referred to as a,
I don't know what you would call it in town, but it's just a hardening of the area with riprap stone.
Once underway,
this operation
should take about ninety days barring any,
you know,
unforeseen interruptions.
We are concerned about
erosion and runoff on this site. This property has several
intermittent
drainage ways or fingers of water that flow from west to east.
We're looking to do this job during mid winter conditions,
during hard frozen conditions, hard freeze conditions,
or
during mid summer conditions when the water tables are at their lowest level.
The property is
rectangular in shape. The
property of butters have been notified
by regular mail
other than that it's a pretty straightforward operation we're just looking for a jurisdictional ruling this is a silvicultural
treatment
and I believe it's a permitted use ever as of right activity
I have
Joe Wagner who was very helpful.
He just sent to me by email the town of Andover,
Inland Wetlands and Water Causes Commission application.
I'm not familiar with that.
I have not had the opportunity
to meet with the landowner and to secure her signature on this, but I'd be more than happy to do so, and get that to you,
pre before the next meeting.
Are there any questions?
>> Okay.
I think that
since we're being asked to make a jurisdictional
ruling here,
I'm going to begin the discussion by making a motion
to the effect
that a
permit
will be required
for
the portion of activity
that involves
actually crossing
water courses
and where you have
what we have been advised is the deposition of materials
in
a wetlands or water course.
So,
again, I'll make that motion and ask for a second by a member of the Commission.
Jed will second.
>> Okay, so we have a motion and a second.
And with that on the floor, we can discuss
the proposed activity.
First, any comments from the
members of the commission?
>> Wouldn't
us having jurisdictional
authority
be consistent with what
our legal attorney has
given us for guidance in the past and what we've done in the past?
>> Exactly
so. We have,
you know, there's already precedent
for
requiring
a permit
for this activity. Again, it's not the silviculture per se,
it's the
wetlands crossing or watercourse crossing
and
wetlands disposition
aspect of the
silviculture
operation, which the silviculture is, as you observed,
permitted as of right
under Connecticut statutes.
But that sort of that's
not inclusive of every aspect
of the
operation.
And again, we were advised by legal counsel
and have previously
required
applications
or
permit applications
for
forestry operations
and silviculture operations
that entail crossing
watercourse
and using
either temporary bridge or corduroy to
affect that crossing.
It's again
pretty straightforward
based on our
previous
dispositions,
and as I said, the advice
of our
attorney,
who's of course, versed in
what was regulations.
I don't know if you've run into this in other jurisdictions,
this is a while, but
that's the way it's played out recently Me
on this matter?
Yeah, go ahead. Okay.
>> I think the key word here is,
I'm
fine with making an application.
I don't have a problem with that. I get paid for what I do.
I think the key word here is deposition.
Depositing something
inorganic into a wetlands. I think you'll find that's how the legislation reads. The placement of a permanent
a temporary stream crossing, a portable bridge,
is not by definition the placement of something into a wetlands. The first crossing, which is a corduroy crossing, which historically was used as a corduroy crossing
previously.
Yeah, you're putting organic matter, which is in this case logs,
into a temporary stream crossing and you're removing them later.
That by definition
could be considered deposition of something into a wetlands.
To get around that, if you'd prefer,
we could put another
set of portable bridges on the first crossing,
thereby
avoiding any deposition and not putting the corduroy in and just using two portable bridges. I think by definition,
we've now avoided on both crossing any deposition of anything into a watercourse or wetlands.
And that's how I understand the legislation. I just wanted to open that discussion.
>> Okay. Agent Wagner, do you have
any comment on that
point? Again, as I say, our attorney advises that
exactly analogous activities, that is temporary crossing,
temporary bridging,
or corduroy,
would be regarded as deposition, even though it's deposition
and subsequent removal.
>> The the
the thing that those
previous applications that he was referring to were,
the the temporary crossings were
corduroy placed into
the stream,
which as, Mr. Dubois pointed out, where, well, you know, that could be considered film.
I believe there were no
temporary bridges,
which would,
>> if I understand it correctly, that would that would the one Kieber Road did involve temporary bridging.
I wasn't
on the commission at that point.
>> Right.
I know you weren't the agent then,
but I'll have to go back into the record
to get the exact
circumstances.
I'm
working on
incomplete
memory here. But
as I said, the fact is that we were advised,
and I would have to, again,
I would want to review the
statutory,
well, the regulation.
I do have here. I got it out. Okay,
good. It's
>> Was this section 4.1?
The section of it that pertains it would be the provisions of
this subdivision.
So the following operations and uses shall be permitted in inland wetlands and water courses and upland review areas as of right. That's grazing, farming, nursery,
gardening, and harvesting of crops and farm ponds of three acres or less essential to the farming app operation,
and activities conducted by or under the authority of the Department of Environmental Protection.
Then the one that pertains to us, the provisions of the subdivision
shall not be construed to include
road construction or the direction of buildings not directly related to the farming operation,
relocation of wetlands with continual flow, filling or reclamation of wetlands or water courses with continual flow,
clear cutting of timber.
That's what pertains to it. So when I when I look at it, I see
relocation of wetlands or watercourses with continual flow
or filling a reclamation of wetlands or watercourses with continual flow. So placing
corduroy in the wetland
would probably fall under that,
whereas
placing a bridge span or
the water course would not.
So that's what what I would see. I would I would
my my
thought would be that a permit would be required if corridor was placed in
the wetland, or if any kind of fill
was placed in the wetland, whereas a bridge span over it would
not be
considered fill.
>> Okay.
Let me add here that I think we'd be, speaking to the Commission. I believe we'd be disposed to approve this activity.
It's just that,
given our understanding of the circumstances and the actions that you're proposing,
that
a permit
is required
for the crossings.
Again, under the OCNIV
4.3,
which basically says that
unless it's specifically permitted,
it requires permit
by
regulations.
And I don't see anything in the regulations that specifically
state
that you know, temporary
bridge or corduroy is
permitted
as an activity or rut.
>> I
beg to differ. I'm not here to argue you, but Joe Wagner just read the regulations
into the record.
And his position is that a temporary stream crossing
is not a regulated activity under state jurisdiction.
I propose that if you have an issue with the corduroy and the first crossing, that we would install a second set of temporary bridges,
which I'm prepared to do, which would be non jurisdictional
based on Joe's interpretation of the regulations.
Again, I'm not trying to argue. I'm just pointing out facts.
Mr. Chairman,
for
the record,
I have no problem whatsoever
with filing the application with you and coming back to the next meeting. I just want to clarify
that in any other jurisdiction in
this state,
the placement of a temporary portable bridge is a non regulated activity.
But out of respect to you and your commission, I will file a complete application for the next meeting. Have no problem with that. I get paid to do what I do. Right. Well, we're still in the process of deciding whether you need to do Okay. Okay?
>> And
again, I'm
basing my comments
so far
to the
previous
situations
where we've had stream crossings
as part of silviculture
operations.
>> I remember the last operation I did for the town of Andover behind the Andover School, which that property we've thinned twice so far, there was a temporary stream crossing
that was hardened.
Weren't required to place temporary bridges. It goes back a long time ago. John Valenti was involved then, great guy.
And so but the rules have changed since then, and regulations get interpreted differently. And I understand that. I'm very
comfortable with filing a complete application if you want me to do it. No problem.
>> Right.
Okay.
Let me ask again for comments
from the commissioners.
Mr. Wasson?
>> Yeah, so,
and again, it might not be something that we would have jurisdiction on with this temporary bridge,
but I'm not familiar,
know, and I didn't see any information
in the package on the temporary bridge,
but
just seem to me if we were bringing logs across temporary bridge, that would have to be a pretty robust structure.
And I don't have a feel for
how big the stream is that we're crossing with this temporary bridge.
I think that's a stream that's
in our regulations listed as a stream
of significant concern or whatever the
special concern.
And so,
as a commission member,
I guess I'd like to know more about the bridge that we're going to put over it. The only experience I have with a temporary bridge
is the property that we were trying wrestle with putting a temporary bridge across on, I think it was Cider Mill Road.
And I don't know how that ever came out. I just know it got real hard and I can't remember what happened after that, if we ever approved it or not, but it was not trivial. And so from my own personal understanding, I'd like to have a better
understanding of what the loggers do to make a robust enough temporary bridge to span this without any detriment to the wetlands
or the watercourse near it. Yeah,
>> I agree. I think Jed is
right on, absolutely.
I don't know if Joe had time to get out there and do a site walk and inspection. I'd be more than happy to meet with Joe and other commission members to look at this stream crossing, talk about the placement of bridges. I can also demonstrate what these bridges look like.
Having been in business for forty years, I've got plenty of photos showing how they should be installed properly.
I mean, sometimes they get installed wrong. You got to do it right. And then how they're removed. And then what remedial actions you take to stabilize the stream bed and to, you know, make it good. I'd be I'd be more than happy to go out there with Joe and any commission member, and we can take a look at hopefully,
before the snow flies. It's it's a long it's a long walk out there in snow, so maybe we can get it done sooner than later.
You're muted, George.
>> Oh, George. Yeah, I know. I I muted. I could see the little red thing, and I was fishing around for the unmute
option. Okay, so yeah, again, I take your point, and we would I think that a sidewalk would certainly be appropriate if there's an application.
And again, we haven't decided yet whether you really need to make an application.
Right.
>> Pretty straightforward.
I mean, I have it right here. I mean, it could take me literally twenty
minutes to fill it out.
>> I realize it won't take a look. So
I guess
I'll ask the Commission if we should just sort of cut to the chase right now and
decide,
take
a vote on the motion to
require a permit or to require an application for a permit.
Are we okay with doing that? Do think we need further discussion on
parsing the statute and regulation,
or should we just, again,
rule on the question of whether or not an application will be required?
>> I got a comment on that, Bill Monroe. I
seem to agree with Jed on this. I'd like to at least be able to see this
bridge
that we're talking about so that we can
make a clear decision on it on
this if
we feel we need to have an application or if it's just
not going to do any damage at all and
just okay,
it is a
right of
property owner.
>> Excuse me,
concur with Bill.
Maybe I was remiss. I should have included photos and I do apologize.
Thought everybody was familiar with these structures.
If you go to YouTube
and type in Dubois forestry,
you'll see
a clear picture of what these structures look like. But again, I'm very comfortable with meeting with any of you, Jed, Bill,
Joe, take a walk out there. We'll look at where the bridges are going. I can bring photos at that time and you'll have a clear understanding of it. And I think you'll feel more comfortable looking at it and so will I. I'm fine with that.
>> We have photos on record.
There was a previous application.
The one
that was most recent was over on Cone Road.
And
there you would this is again for the commission.
I don't remember the application
number,
but it involved basically the same sort of activity, although the stream crossing
reduced. It was
an intermittent
water course that was being crossed. But
we have photographs that
Bill could access showing the
squares that
are used
to
do the bridging.
Again, as
Commissioner Larson pointed out, we had the application
for a temporary
crossing of Saddle Brook
lower down below Route
316.
This was for a different activity,
but again a permit to cross the stream using a temporary bridge
that was approved.
You know, it wasn't
They
first, I think, asked for
perhaps a permanent bridge and then
got modified to become a temporary bridge, just the sort that you're describing and proposing to use
on that property. This is the portion of Stout Brook that's just above the swamp,
right? It's
directly
where it's going to run-in.
So
I think that we can
I don't want to delay this too much?
We defer a ruling,
then Well,
let's put it this way. A if you need an application,
we're not going to be able to consider it until next month,
and then we can't approve it for another two weeks. So you know that kind of puts you behind the eight ball
with regard to getting out there while the ground is frozen and hard. Exactly. So,
you know, I don't want to throw up that kind of obstacle,
but at the same time, I want to make sure that we are the
Commission is acting in accordance with its own regulations and precedents,
and that we're not making
too many ad hoc
decisions
about
what is a
permissible activity as of right.
As I said,
it seems to me that this would be a permittable activity.
The other question is whether it's a permittable activity
as of right or whether you need a permit to
apply for the permit.
Again, that's what is current
subject of discussion and the
motion on the floor
to
require
a permit.
Now, if that
motion is
defeated,
then you're free to go ahead. Are operating as of right,
and
you know we trust that
your proposal
meets best management plan
and all that.
If we decide that it does need an application, well, you've got the application in hand and can submit it rapidly. But as I say,
there's no way we can consider it
before our next regular meeting. Understood.
>> Is
it possible that
under the circumstances,
because this operation isn't going to start until mid winter,
so I don't have a problem delaying it, but if it were a jurisdictional ruling, could Joe and I and other commission members get out there kind of on short notice
and take a look at the crossing
and
assess it
and then get back to the commission? Is there any way we could expedite this? Again, I'm not trying to push it along because if we don't get frozen ground conditions, it's not working this winter. We're gonna
going to be out there until next summer, maybe. And then this past summer, we had like five feet of water. So you can't even work in the woods these days. It's unbelievable. I know, I know. We're waiting for things to dry up and it never did. Good luck.
>> Well, I think once we have an application,
we could we might be able to schedule a special meeting
to receive the application.
And, you know, we've got to do all these things as notice meetings, right.
So
I think the fastest way we could do it would be, if you were to submit the application,
we could schedule
a special meeting to receive the application
and
to
take a sidewalk,
you know, to see what you're doing. Those
would be permissible, I think, under FOI,
but we would still have to wait
from our, you know, from our official
receipt of the application.
We'd have to wait two weeks
by
statute before we could act on it.
Now, of course, with the holiday season coming up, I'm not going anywhere, other people might, and you know, I can see where
it
doesn't seem to me impossible that we could do that. Can I add something? I
>> was just thinking that the other option might be to
not
rule on the jurisdictional ruling this month,
and then schedule a sidewalk.
And then.
At the January meeting, you would either rule that it.
It's an as a right use or that it requires a permit, then you could
receive the the applicant, you could either
make the jurisdictional ruling
>> that if it needs a deferment, you could accept it. Yeah,
that would that would
push us off if we receive the application
at our January meeting, you know, assuming we I just don't see any benefit to
deferring
the jurisdictional
ruling.
I think that if we have a jurisdictional ruling
that's clear cut, that's yes or no,
and
the
circumstances of what of exactly how
the bridge is being
laid and exactly where it's going, which is what we see on the sidewalk,
isn't entirely material to the jurisdictional ruling.
Again, the question is, does it need a permit or is it activity as of right?
For nothing. Excuse
>> me, I'm sorry, but not for nothing. I would have had your permit completed
and into you by today. I couldn't get to it and it requires a landowner's signature.
But certainly in the next couple of days, I can fill this
application out and meet with the landowner,
secure her signature, and deliver to the town hall. So I don't have any problem by getting that to you. If you could perhaps schedule whatever
you call a special meeting
expedite it to allow the forest products harvester
time to get in there, say in January or February when ground conditions would be ideal,
that's great. If you could help us out with that, great. If not, I understand.
Understand.
>> So Chairman Elliott, what
date is our January meeting? Do you happen to know? I can't remember if we deferred from the third It's January 11.
>> So I'm looking at my calendar also,
which means we would have to receive the application
absolutely no later
than
Tuesday,
December 28. Now clearly we could, know, you're
obviously in a position to do it sooner than that. Now, the question is, can we schedule a special meeting?
And here's where the commissioners
have to kind of weigh in.
Is
anytime. Mean, typically we do our sidewalks on Saturday mornings,
but it can be anytime that the commissioners are available
and that you're available and that
the property owner will permit us to come on the property and have a look.
I guess that would be the first question. Could we have a
special meeting? Let's see, we need to warn that in advance.
So,
let's say practically speaking,
week,
or maybe the eleventh.
I don't remember off the top of my head how soon we have to warn it, but we have to, for a special meeting, we have to post it
in advance.
So
how does it look to
the commission? Jed, do you have your calendar?
>> I Either the eleventh or the eighteenth would work, and I would hope that we could have a special meeting to accept the application and a site visit
at the same time,
so then at the January meeting we'd be ready to Exactly,
>> we'd be in a position to
vote on and
approve the application
on January 11.
And you know, that's about, you know, hey, that's as fast as it's going to get done
if we decide
to exercise jurisdiction,
okay?
We decide not to exercise jurisdiction,
you're home free.
>> So, I'm
going to fill out the application no matter what, correct? I should fill that out and drop it by in the next few days, right? I mean, that makes sense.
>> Yeah, if
we decide you need an application,
obviously we want that ASAP.
And
then we can
see,
we're
looking at penciling in
Commissioner Monroe
eleventh or eighteenth. Okay, by you.
Eleventh is fine.
Okay.
What about the eighteenth in case we didn't have an opportunity to warn the meeting?
The eighteenth is okay. Okay,
>> and I'm okay for the eleventh or the eighteenth. So, we can pencil, you know, depending on the
receipt of the, know, the application is in,
let's say, when it's in Agent Wagner's hands, and we can warn
a special meeting.
Okay? So the
special
meeting would be either the eleventh or the eighteenth,
typically 09:00
as
a target date
and time
for a sidewalk.
And as I say, it would also be our opportunity
to formally receive the application
and
put us in a position to vote on it.
Okay,
so we're all clear on that on on the contingencies.
Okay, so we still have to vote on the motion. I still have a quick question for Joe.
>> Just if I get this application
filled out and signed by the landowner,
do you work out of the Andover town hall office?
Yes. Yeah. So I can deliver it to you there physically?
>> Yeah. You can well, you can if I'm not there, you can deliver it to the building Okay. Admin, and then I can get it. So or you can email it either way. Yeah. I'll give you a hard copy.
Okay.
My paper is long memory.
>> Okay. So George, can I make one quick point? This is Eric Anderson. Yeah, we're And that is, you would have to have, if you're gonna do a special meeting on Saturday,
because the town hall is officially closed Friday,
you would have to notice that on Thursday.
>> Okay,
so thanks for
that. So it would have to be noticed on the ninth
for the eleventh
and
no later than we'll
we know we'll have it in time to warrant it for the eighteenth. The only tight schedule would be trying to warrant it for
a special meeting on the eleventh.
So
thanks for chiming in, Eric.
We'll
know how we have to move
once the application is received. Again,
depending on the vote on the motion, which I'm going to call that because I think we've discussed this just about to death.
I'm going ask for a vote on the motion regarding
jurisdictional
regarding the Commission's jurisdiction
over this activity and whether an application is
required.
Again, the motion was that it
was affirmative, that is to say that an application would be required
for the portion of the activity occurring in
wetlands that are crossing the water course.
And
so an affirmative vote is that you would need to file that application.
So,
by roll call, I will ask for a vote.
Commissioner Larson?
Aye.
Mr. Monroe?
>> And I, Chairman Elliot, also vote aye. So, the
motion passes
three-zero-zero.
We have ruled jurisdiction
and an application
is required, and we expect it will be forthcoming.
We'll try and move this on as quick as we can and expect to meet no later than December 18
to receive
the application
and to
take a sidewalk
and
have you explain
the activity.
>> Two more questions, if I may. Yeah, go ahead.
At the sidewalk, is a quorum required by the Commission?
Yes, because it is a meeting.
>> Okay.
Well, I just want to make sure that no one's wasting their time and having an inadequate number of members show up and not having a quorum. That would be I'll
>> poll beforehand
to make sure that we will be present.
Okay, wonderful. We will, you know, yeah, I understand
the frustration
of,
suppose they had a meeting and nobody came.
We will certainly want to avoid that.
And yeah, we will have a quorum for a formal meeting.
And you know, and as I say, any sidewalk
is technically a meeting. We have to have a quorum. We have to mourn the meeting. We have to provide minutes to the meeting.
It will be straightforward.
>> Joe,
or who will be notifying me of the date whether it's the eleventh or the eighteenth who will be telling me what date it is?
>> I could I can send you the the date.
Okay.
>> I was gonna say our our agent is generally in charge of setting
up the agenda and posting
the morning
online for the meeting. So yeah, you'll hear from him. And again, as I said, I will make sure of a quorum
beforehand.
Okay.
>> All right, I'll get this application to you, Joe, in the next,
I mean, probably the next few days. If you're not in the office, I'll just drop it by the office. This building is closed on Fridays.
>> Yeah, yeah, they're open.
Building
apartments open till 01:15 every day except for Friday.
That was part time.
So and then there's a drop
box in the front that if
no one's there, you could leave it in there.
>> Alright. I'll find you. Yeah. Are you still downstairs on the right where where John Valenti was?
>> Yeah.
The well, the building office is on the right, and my office is on the left, but, yeah, we're in the same area. Okay. Somebody will be here. Alright.
>> Very good. Okay. Thank you. Thank you for your time and patience with this process.
Okay. Okay,
moving on then. We now
find the agenda again here.
Oh, yeah, okay, we're next, we're going to actually deal with
old business.
We have
three permit applications
that are currently pending.
The first,
application number
from the Kohl's
for
rebuilding a stone stairway
into
Andover Lake.
To facilitate
moving on this, I'm going to make a motion that we approve the application,
and I'll take a second.
I'll second that.
>> Thank you. One more. Okay, so we have a motion and a second to
approve the application,
and
I'll ask if there's
any
discussion.
I'm all set.
Okay.
Commissioner Monroe, did you have any? All
set.
>> Okay, yeah, it seemed to be pretty straightforward,
and I think we covered it
thoroughly
at the last meeting when we received
the application.
So,
seeing no further questions from the Commission, I'll proceed to a vote.
Commissioner Larson?
Aye.
Commissioner Munro?
And I also vote aye. So, the motion carries three-zero.
Next, we have Permit Application
2,122,
applicant Jeff Miner for the owner Ellen Galmott at 326 Lake Road
to rebuild
an existing lake wall.
Again,
to facilitate,
I will
move that we
approve the permit in standard conditions, two years
duration.
Any
Okay, Anita, we need a second.
I'll second.
>> Okay, so I moved and seconded to approve
any questions
or comments
on the
application?
Commissioner Larson, any questions or views?
>> I can't remember from the drawing of this one,
but the question
for Marcy
would be,
does this have the crushed stone behind the stone walls to act as a little filtering medium or whatever to
as we go to the stonewall.
>> I said, yes, does.
Yes. Actually, I'm Jeff Miner. That's me in the hat and glasses.
Okay.
>> That's my nighttime attire.
But to answer the question, yes, there will be crushed stone with a fabric as a filter.
>> And would that crushed stone go all the way to the surface or would that be up harsh way and then covered with dirt?
>> It would be probably within
five to six inches of
the top level of the wall, then yes, it would be backfilled with
topsoil and seeded
with an erosion mat.
Okay,
I have no other questions.
Okay.
Commissioner Monroe.
I'm all set.
>> Okay.
And,
yeah, I think that the
well, Commissioner Larson already
asked a question
about the wall
rebuild,
and I think, again, we covered the
area and so forth. So
if there is no further discussion,
we can proceed to a vote on the motion,
which is to approve
the permit application with standard conditions and
for a two year duration be adequate?
>> Yes, it would be for me, yes. Okay, so two year,
>> again
ask for a roll call vote. Commissioner
Larson.
Aye. Now, Commissioner Monroe.
Aye.
>> And I also vote aye. So the motion carries three zero zero.
I guess that as soon as the ground is ready, you can get going on the work.
Awesome. Two weeks,
and two then Two weeks? Yeah,
right. There's always that delay
required
for public comment and the publication of legal notice.
>> Sounds good. We won't be ready before that anyway. Okay, and
>> I'm sure you'll be in touch with Agent Wagner
if the activity proceeds.
Sounds good, thank you.
>> Okay,
moving on.
Let's see now. Let me close out this one.
I can never decide whether shuffling paper
or clicking on files
is slower
and
more prone to error
in finding what you're looking for.
'22, we're looking for
a permit application number
from the town of Andover, and of course, that's the
sidewalk that we completed on Saturday.
Okay, yeah, here it is.
So,
again, I'll kick it off by
making a motion to the effect that we approve
the application
with
standard conditions
and for a two year duration.
Oops, I keep clicking on new folder rather than open.
One second.
>> So we have a motion and a second to
approve the application
from the town of Andover.
And I see that our
town administrator, Eric Anderson, is still on the call and probably
wants to refresh her memory
on what's going to happen here.
Do we have any questions from the Commissioners
following the sidewalk on Saturday?
I'm all set. Okay.
I am pretty much too. We saw
and
Jay
described
what's
going to be done, the trail going up
across
the
rail trail
and
upward towards Merritt Valley Road, presumably with
eventual access to the Stearns Park
area across Merritt Valley Road from the town owned property we recently acquired along Cheney Brook,
and the clearing and
work that would be done to create a picnic area.
So, if there are no questions
or comments from the members,
I don't have any. Thought it was pretty straightforward and willing to proceed to the vote. So,
Commissioner Larson.
Aye.
Commissioner Monroe.
And I also vote aye. So, the motion is approved
three zero zero.
Alright. You can have them get to it as soon as they can get a get that round to it.
>> Fair enough. Gentlemen, thank you all,
for your attention to this matter. And with that, I will bid you a good night. You are free to leave.
>> Take care.
Okay, moving on with the agenda.
We don't have any active enforcement
actions,
and we have only one
permit
under the AGER report.
Major Weiner, did you have any comments on that
permit application
2125?
>> I just had a one actually,
if we could go back to enforcement actions, I just had an update.
On 93
Townsend Road.
The shipping containers in the Upland Review area.
They were
moved out of the area on December
2.
Notified me that they were gone. I took a ride by there.
No longer
next to the wetland.
>> Good enough.
But here that hadn't been downtowns and road for a few days, so I hadn't seen that done. Yeah, it was just it was late really late last week.
>> And then the the permit application, the IWWC
21 Dash 25 was just a it was a gravel driveway
and associated
they they made a
proposed
a little grass strange whale that would kind of follow the existing
contours.
And that was within
100 foot upland review area of an unnamed Brook, there was it's
if you're heading
down,
like heading north on West Road,
down towards
Andover Lakes and the
Brook is
above an elevation
above the proposed driveway.
So everything
that they're proposing would kind of keep the same contours and the same drainage pattern and
drain it into the culvert that goes under the road.
So that's a pretty straightforward, pretty detailed application.
But I wish more of them were like that.
>> Yeah, don't we all? I
take it that, yeah, I saw the photographs, and in this case, the upland review is actually
downhill
of
the brook,
but still within the radius. And so, can expect obviously minimal impact clearly
from rural. I take it they're going to develop that property if they want to drive it. Yeah, you needed access. The lot is in the rear, so needed to access the
building area. Yeah. Okay.
Okay,
well then moving on,
item 10: Other business. We do have I was remiss.
I overlooked in the IWWC
chair
inbox
with Microsoft Outlook.
I don't review it very often, and I overlooked
the memo
from
Prime Minister, well, from actually from Amanda
about
the annual reports
being due about a month and a half ago, and
so I finally got around to it last week.
I distributed that
to the
commissioners
and wanted to see if I think I copied you on that also,
Joe. So,
anyhow, if anybody has any
corrections
or
whatnot,
I'd be happy to entertain them. Otherwise, I will submit it forthwith,
with apologies
and humbly contrition.
>> My only comment, George, was should we put is one of our goals to get some more members on the Commission?
>> Yeah, I think that's a reasonable
goal.
Since I did comment on the fact that we're presently
operating with a bare quorum.
And the only thing I can add a sense to that effect.
>> One thing I saw in there was that I remember talking about this when I first.
Got the job here. We're talk it was it's goal number two
on there,
developing separate applications
for administrative approvals, permit modification requests, and jurisdictional ruling requests.
I'm not sure if we ever
do that permit link thing, that's only, it's like one
application,
and then I, you know, after thinking about it, I kind of think it's a lot less confusing if we
just stick to one
application,
because then, you know, basically the same amount of information required for
either an administrative approval or a regular
wetlands application. You just need enough information
to, you know, make a determination.
So
I think I think just keeping one application would be good. And then
same with permit modification. It makes a lot easier for the billing office too if everything was just under one, so they wouldn't have to guess which one they needed for certain things if there was any question.
And then as for jurisdictional rulings, I think I've seen other towns that
have you fill out an application
along with the jurisdictional
ruling so that if you
make the ruling that a permit's required, then you can just receive the application at the same meeting. I think that's a good idea. That's kinda what I was trying to get
mister Dubois to do,
but he kinda ran out of time because it was it was submitted a little late.
But my my thought going forward was we try to get him to put the application in and then, yeah, if you
if it's as a right, great. If not, then accept the application at that meeting, and then, you know, have to delay any
any more necessary.
>> Right. But that's just a process thing, not a separate application. You're right. And frankly, just carried that forward because, hey, it was in
our previous annual report, something we hadn't done, and we still hadn't done it. So, I figured that it should be carried forward. But I take your point, and
I have
a quick
poll in the
commission here, whether
this is a goal we want to retain here.
Again, this is future
goals and priorities number two.
Okay.
So anybody want to weigh in on that,
Jud?
I
>> don't have a copy of the annual report in front of me. I just read it online,
so I can't remember what it said.
But if it has anything to do with getting that application in when we do the jurisdictional ruling, I think tonight proved the point
on how that's a great idea.
>> Yeah. No, the point here was whether we want to retain,
again, reads, developing separate applications for administrative approvals,
permit modification requests,
and jurisdictional
ruling requests.
That was stated as a goal
for
FY twenty twenty one-twenty two,
and
Agent Wagner is pointing out that maybe that's a goal that's not worth retaining,
with which I've been calling to agree.
>> Yeah, I agree with Agent Wagner that we should be using the same application
for, you know, either case.
>> Okay, Commissioner Munro, anything you want to weigh in on? It sounds like it would be wise to just have one application.
>> Okay,
so one application with maybe an improved process
regarding jurisdictional
reviews, but I can drop that as a goal.
So, consider that excised
from the draft
annual report.
Okay.
But oh, apropos of, goal number one, I still haven't heard
from
Department of
Energy and Environmental Protection
regarding
whether a hearing or whether
they have any comment
on our proposed
update and revision
of
the IWWC
regulations.
If we don't hear from them,
or if I don't hear from them by our January
meeting,
I think we can probably just go ahead and schedule a hearing pro form a
and
be in a position
to approve
those regulation updates
finally
after about
two years
of
hit and miss effort.
So, returning then to the question of the annual report, if those are the two things we basically add a goal
of
bringing our membership up to
full capacity
with
five members and three alternates.
God, that's a lot of people.
But anyhow, we'll see what we can do about,
you know, Addison's
goal, a substitute of Goal two
for the present Goal two.
Again, I'll circulate that for
a quick review
before I submit it
to
Amanda
for the record and for incorporation in the annual report for the town.
>> With respect to membership, you know,
the way I understand it is if we have a five member commission
and three members are attending a meeting, so we have a quorum,
all three need to vote in favor
of a
motion before it can pass.
>> Which is a constraint, but you're absolutely right.
If if there's any dissent,
then
it fails.
>> Okay, yep, just want to make sure I understood what the rules were on the voting.
>> So,
that's another good incentive
to
try to restore our membership.
The
tentative inquiries we've had
haven't
resulted in any further action,
and
I guess there were constraints
on some interests
with respect to being a registered voter and so on and so forth.
But I guess it's probably time to get out and
beat the bushes,
figuratively speaking,
and
try to
again try to enlist
at least a couple of members
to
get us up to voting strength.
So, any other comments on the annual report?
Okay, if not,
we can move on
to the subject of number 11,
which I must say
took me by surprise.
I didn't know that Zoom had a time machine function.
In fact, our next
regular meeting will be Monday, 01/11/2022
at 7PM.
Oh yeah, screwed
>> that up. Yes, Tuesday, January 11, right? How easy it is to carry things forward one way or the other.
Okay,
writing the wrong year done early.
>> Okay,
we'll
get it right for the minutes, right, Abby?
So,
with that,
I can
ask for unanimous
consent
on adjournment at 08:36PM.
Seeing no dissent,
we'll consider the meeting adjourned.
I will thank you all for
participating,
and I still don't have an answer from Abby.
Down in the chat.
Oh, I sent you a message back at the beginning.
This has got nothing to do with it. It's got nothing to do with the meeting.
>> I don't think I got a chat. You'll have to tell me other somewhere else. Oh, well, asked you if you planted garlic.
Oh, yes, at the garden, ready
in the summer. A had
>> warm fall, I figured it would probably be okay. It should root up. And in fact, the stuff that I planted at home in
early October,
which is normally when you should be planting, is all sprouted up.
And of course, it's all going to get the
green above ground.
It's all going to get totally frozen
by the time it's time to grow again.
It was an oddball. That really may have been a little mistake.
We'll see how it works out when comparing notes
next July. Okay,
so that was the
extraneous conversation.
And once again, we'll consider the meeting adjourned. Then everybody can press the little red leave button, and Abby can
end the meeting
at her leisure. Good night, everybody.
Night. Not at all.